Howard McClusky Collection
Howard McClusky Collection
- Journal articles
  - JA-321: Reactions of Teachers to the Teaching situation - A study of job satisfaction, reprinted from The Journal Review, Vol. XLV, No 8, co-authored with Floyd J. Strayer, October 1940 (Box 3)
  - JA-33: Mobilizing the Community for Adult Education, in The Quarterly Review, April 29, 1939 (Box 3)
  - JA-34: Reducing the error of the Guesstimate, in Michigan Education Journal, September 1, 1959 (Box 3)
  - JA-35: Some Propositions in Support of the Community School, in The Journal of Educational Sociology, undated (Box 3)
  - JA-36: It's happening here! Several Michigan Communities are developing Total Educational Resources through Cooperative Planning Branch County, Dowagiac and Hartland Pioneer, in Michigan Educational Journal, April 1939 (Box 3)
  - JA-38: Adult and Community Education: Its Promise and Relevance, in Community Educational Journal Volume 1, Number 3, August, 1971 (Box 3)
  - JA-39: Where can we look for leadership? in Phi Delta Kappan, November 1972 (Box 3)
  - JA-41: An experimental comparison of the Methods of Correcting the Outcome of an Examination, reprinted from School and Society Vol 40, No. 1035, October 1934 (Box 3)
  - JA-48: Mechanical Aids to Education and the new teacher - a Prophecy, reprinted from Education, October, 1934 (Box 3)
  - JA-50: An Experiment on the influence of Preliminary Skimming on Reading, reprinted from Journal of Educational Psychology, October, 1934 (Box 3)
  - JA-51: An Experimental Study of Language Patterns, reprinted from the English Journal Vol. XXV No 1, co-authored with Creighton Coleman, January, 1936 (Box 3)
  - JA-52: An Experimental Comparison of the New Type Test and the Term Paper, reprinted from Journal of Applied Psychology, Vol. XV no. 5, October, 1933 (Box 3)
  - JA-53: Some propositions in support of the community school - a summary, in Journal of Educational Sociology, December, 1959 (Box 3)
  - JA-61: What do we want for our children? in the National Parent Teacher Magazine, February, 1953 (Box 3)
  - JA-63: Youth in Search of Happiness in National Parent Teacher Magazine, March, 1940 (Box 3)
  - JA-66: The First Fifty Years of the School of Education and Beyond, in the Innovator, 1971 (Box 3)
  - JA-71: An experience of Hypothyroidism: A case study, reprinted from the Journal of Abnormal and Social Psychology, Vol XXIX No 4, January - March, 1935 (Box 3)
- Monographs
  - MO-1: The information self-help approach in approaches to community development, 1973 (Box 3)
  - MO-3: Pre-Conference Study Guide of the National Conferences of the Adult Education Association of the US, November 11-13, 1955; McClusky was co-chairman of the sub-committee (Box 3)
  - MO-4: Connecticut Teacher Volume 1X N2, November. 1941; Contains program for convention day on which McClusky was expected to speak (Box 3)
  - MO-5: Innovator, Volume 1 No.3, C, January, 1970; contains information about McClusky (Box 3)
  - MO-6: Bureau of Studies and Training in Community Adult Education, in University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, Vol.19, February, 1948 (Box 3)
  - MO-7: Directory of Community Councils in Michigan, by Community and Adult Education Department of University of Michigan, 1957; McClusky was Chairman and wrote a "Foreword" to this directory (Box 3)
  - MO-8: School Responsibility for the Education of Adults, in the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, April, 1951 (Box 3)
  - MO-9: The Mentors -- Educational Values in Transition: New Dimensions, in Living The Beginnings: Interviews with the mentors, March 1-2, 1974; McClusky was one of the mentors (Box 3)
  - MO-10: "Some Current Trends in Community Organization" in Adult Education Bulletin, February 1946 (Box 3)
  - MO-11: How Community Agencies May Help with Problems of Delinquency, an offprint of Chapter IX (pp.191-213) of the Forty-Seventh Yearbook, Part I, 1948 (Box 3)
  - MO-12: Mental Hygiene and the Public School, An article in the University of Michigan: School of Education Bulletin, Vol.4, No.1 October 1932 (Box 4)
  - MO-13: The Education of the Gifted Child, in the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, Vol. 3, Number 5, February, 1932 (Box 4)
  - MO-14: Conference proceedings of Georgia's Human Resources Third Annual Conference, undated; McClusky was a key speaker (Box 4)
  - MO-15: Community Seminar for Adult Education, in the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, Vol. 10 Number 5, February, 1939 (Box 4)
  - MO-16: The Responsibility of the Public School for Adult Education published in Now... In Our Town, February, 1945 (Box 4)
  - MO-17: The Optimum Development of Older Rural youth, in The Contribution of Extension Methods and Techniques Toward the Rehabilitation of War-torn Countries, pp. 215-217, September 19-22, 1944 (Box 4)
  - MO-18: Community education/development, co-authored with J. Lin Compton, January, 1978 (Box 4)
  - MO-18.1: The relevance of psychology for adult education. Later a chapter in Adult Education: An Emerging Field of University Study, ca. 1964 (Box 4)
  - MO-19: "Education for Community Leadership" in Cranbrook Bulletin, Spring-Summer, 1944 (Box 4)
  - MO-20: On Placing Facts in Their Proper Setting, in the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, Vol 11, No. 4, January 1940 (Box 4)
  - MO-22: Adult Education and the Public School, in the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin. Vol. 16, No.5, February 1945 (Box 4)
  - MO-23: The School and the Future of the Mental Hygiene Movement, reprinted from the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, Vol. 8, No. 2, November 1936 (Box 4)
  - MO-24: A Neglected Laboratory for the Study of Youth, in the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, Vol. 1, No. 3, December 1929 (Box 4)
  - MO-26: Community Projects in Adult Education in Michigan, in Community Service News, September- October, 1947 (Box 4)
  - MO-28: Adult Education - Our Secret Weapon, in Adult Leadership, October 1952 (Box 4)
  - MO-29: What is the Mental Hygiene Movement Doing to the Schools? reprinted from the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, Vol. 34, Number 6, March 1963 (Box 4)
  - MO-31: Community-Adult Education at the University of Michigan, reprinted from the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin Vol. 29, Number 1, co-authored with Gale E. Jensen, October 1957 (Box 4)
  - MO-32: The Demand for Continual Learning in Modern Society, reprinted from the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, Volume 34, No. 8, May 1963 (Box 4)
  - MO-33: Howard Y. McClusky and the community councils idea: A bibliographical essay, by Douglas Kelley, February, 1980 (Box 4)
  - MO-34: The Educative Community in The Community School and its Administration, Vol. V No.9, May, 1967 (Box 4)
  - MO-35: The Best Present Ever in Action Newsletter, Vol. 9, Number 5 (pages 1-3), December 1957 (Box 4)
  - MO-37: The Course of the Adult Life Span, May 1963 (Box 4)
  - MO-38: The founding assembly, in Adult Leadership, September, 1975 (Box 4)
  - MO-40: The Educator and His Reading, reprinted from the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, February, 1935 (Box 4)
  - MO-41: The Future of Camping, reprinted from The Camping Magazine Vol IX No. 2, February 1937 (Box 4)
  - MO-43: The Adult Education Program, in the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, Vol 15, No. 4 p. 57, January, 1944 (Box 4)
  - MO-44: The Department of Adult Education, in the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin,, Vol 22, No.7, April, 1951 (Box 4)
  - MO-45: Self-Help, in The Michigan Alumnus Vol LV No 17, March 26, 1949 (Box 4)
  - MO-57: The Rape of Culture, an NBC Radio Discussion by Howard McClusky and Others, in the University of Chicago Round Table, Number 616, January 8, 1950 (Box 4)
  - MO-61: Can Adults Learn Community Self-Help, in the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, Vol 17 Number 5, February, 1946 (Box 4)
  - MO-62: What research says about adult learning potential and about teaching older adults, in Adult learning: Issues and innovations, Northern Illinois University, 1975 (Box 4)
  - MO-63: Speculations on the future of education, in University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, January, 1954 (Box 4)
  - MO-64: Twelve years of community councils in Michigan, in University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, May, 1949 (Box 4)
- Outside reports
  - OR-1: Year 1 AEA First Annual Report of the Adult Education Association of the USA, June 1, 1951 - May 31, 1952 (Box 4)
  - OR-2: A Manuscript on Rural Education Prepared by the Committee on Rural Education, March 24, 1942; McClusky was a committee member (Box 4)
  - OR-3: The Department of Community Adult Education, October 15, 1963 (Box 4)
  - OR-4: The Liberal Arts Colleges Training Community Leaders, in The Inauguration of Herbert Carleton Mayer as Thirteenth President of Parsons College, October 13, 1941 (Box 4)
  - OR-5: First Michigan Teachers Education Workshop, October, 1941 (Box 4)
  - OR-6: Consultant's Report to the School Community Relations Subcommittee of the Citizens Advisory Committee on School Needs, Detroit, Michigan, 1958 (Box 4)
  - OR-8: Development of the Rural Project in Michigan, January 30, 1941 (Box 5)
  - OR-9: The AEA-USA: Why and What it must be, 1971 (Box 5)
  - OR-11: The Future Belongs to Youth (missing as of 12/4/2008), July 2, 1940?
  - OR-12: The Occupational Adjustment of Youth (missing as of 12/4/2008), July 3, 1940?
  - OR-13: Memorandum to Dr. E. L. Kirkpatrick on the Project for Rural Youth, undated (Box 5)
  - OR-14: Area Conference Report. General Plan for Organization, January 1950 (Box 5)
  - OR-15: Flint Eighth Annual Community Education Workshop, October 31, 1963 (Box 5)
  - OR-21: The AEA-USA: Why and What it must be, October, 1971 (Box 5)
  - OR-23: Pre-conference Study Guide: The Role of Adult Education in the Development of the Local Community, by a sub-committee, November, 1955; McClusky was a co-chairman (Box 5)
  - OR-24: Meeting notes, unknown organization (Box 5)
  - OR-26: Committing the Non Committing: Proceedings of the 4th Annual Midwestern Conference on Garden Clubs, November 29-30, 1966 (Box 5)
  - OR-27: The Experimental Program of the American Youth Commission in the Ten CCC Camps of the Fifth Corps Area, undated (Box 5)
  - OR-28: Report entitled "Rural Education Today and Tomorrow" of the Committee on Rural Education, April 22, 1943; McClusky was committee member (Box 5)
  - OR-42: Thirty-Second Annual Convention of the Michigan Hospital Association, November 11-13, 1951 (Box 5)
  - OR-43: The American Youth Commission and the Education of Out-of -School Youth, July 3, 1940 (Box 5)
- Speeches
  - SP-1: On Effective Personality, notes, undated (Box 5)
  - SP-2: Speech at Indiana Rural youth Dinner, notes, January 11, 1944 (Box 5)
  - SP-3: Speech notes, October 25, 1943 (Box 5)
  - SP-4: Speech notes on Trends in Current Social Scene, undated (Box 5)
  - SP-5: Speech notes on Community Participation for Family Living, undated (Box 5)
  - SP-6: Speech notes to the League of Women Voters, April 3, 1961 (Box 5)
  - SP-7: Speech notes to Illinois Congress of Parents and Teachers (loose papers), January 25, 1944 (Box 5)
  - SP-8: Speech notes on Trend in Community Education at Educational Conference (loose papers), July 27, 1944 (Box 5)
  - SP-9: The Adult as Person - A Recapitulative Brief (speech notes in loose papers) (Box 5)
  - SP-10: Neighborhood Democracy, June 5, 1939 (Box 5)
  - SP-11: Speech notes Adult Education at Floral Park, September 1955 (Box 5)
  - SP-11.1: Speech notes to: Governor Kelley’s Committee, January 17, 1944 (Box 5)
  - SP-12: Speech notes to: Great Lakes Regional Camping Association YWCA, Detroit, January 13, 1945 (Box 5)
  - SP-13: Speech notes to Toledo dinner Meeting of Family Life Education and Mental Hygiene Council, June 5, 1944 (Box 5)
  - SP-15: Speech notes to Utah School Administrators' Conference on The Community Centered School, March 29, 1968 (Box 5)
  - SP-16: Speech notes for National Community School Education Association Carillon Hotel, Miami Beach, December 1, 1967 (Box 5)
  - SP-17: Speech notes for Michigan School Board Association on Communicating with Our Public, September 20, 1967 (Box 5)
  - SP-18: Speech notes, Oregon Parks and Recreation Society, January 13, 1967 (Box 5)
  - SP-19: Speech notes, Sears, Garden Clubs, University of Michigan, on Committing the Non-Committed, November 29, 1966 (Box 5)
  - SP-20: Speech notes, Community Power and Community School Director, April 3, 1968 (Box 5)
  - SP-21: Speech notes to Librarians, Audio Visualists, October 20, 1966 (Box 5)
  - SP-22: Speech, Re-discovering the Community: Some new Frontiers for Physical Education, Saskatchewan Physical Education Association, Fort Qu'Appelle, April 5, 1968 (Box 5)
  - SP-23: Speech notes, VISTA - MARQUETTE, June 27, 1966 (Box 5)
  - SP-24: Speech notes, Illinois Adult Education Association, Urbana, University of Illinois, April 26, 1968 (Box 5)
  - SP-25: Speech notes to a country club, May 17, 1956 (Box 5)
  - SP-26: Speech notes to Community Council, October 15, 1964 (Box 5)
  - SP-27: Speech notes on Teacher, Classroom and Society, September 26, 1964 (Box 5)
  - SP-28: Speech notes on Community Influences and Community Responsibility in Guidance, June 26, 1962 (Box 5)
  - SP-29: Speech notes on New Frontiers in Child Guidance and Mental Health, February 2, 1965 (Box 5)
  - SP-30: Speech notes to University of Michigan Resident Counselors, August 22, 1966 (Box 5)
  - SP-31: Speech notes on The Positive View of the Later Years: The Bright side of Retirement, March 6, 1980 (Box 5)
  - SP-32: Speech notes on Mental Hygiene Approach to Guidance Ball State Teachers College, April 16, 1947 (Box 5)
  - SP-33: Speech notes to the National 4-H Club Congress, Stevens Hotel, Chicago, on Civic-Educational Values For a Better Home and World Community, December 2, 1947 (Box 5)
  - SP-34: Speech notes on Program Could not exist without a community, undated (Box 6)
  - SP-35: Educative impact of school materials for adults (?), August 31, 1960 (Box 6)
  - SP-36: Speech notes to conference on Schools, Education and Older People, September 21-23, 1977; McClusky participated as Professor Emeritus (Box 6)
  - SP-37: Speech notes to Ecumenical Workshop on Religion and Aging, on The Older Adult: Potential in Church Setting, May 11, 1977 (Box 6)
  - SP-38: Speech notes to Chelsea High School Commencement, on How to live all of your life, June 9, 1967 (Box 6)
  - SP-39: Speech notes to Alcona Community School Commencement, on How to life all of your life, June 2, 1966 (Box 6)
  - SP-40: Speech notes to Virginia Griffin Concepts/postulate, undated (Box 6)
  - SP-41: Speech notes to Phi Delta Kappa, on The Learning Society and Implications for Education, July 30, 1970 (Box 6)
  - SP-42: Speech to the American Youth Commission of the American Council on Education, on The Future Belongs to Youth, July 2, 1940; McClusky was Associate Director of the commission (Box 6)
  - SP-43: Speech to the American Youth Commission of the American Council on Education, on The Occupational Adjustment of Youth, July 3, 1940; McClusky was Associate of the Commission (Box 6)
  - SP-44: Speech notes to National Community School Education Association, December 1, 1967 (Box 6)
  - SP-45: Where we are...Where are we going?, March 30, 1967; speaker not indicated but it seems to be McClusky's speech (Box 6)
  - SP-46: Progressive Education Chicago, undated; first draft; author not indicated, but it seems to be McClusky's work (Box 6)
  - SP-47: Speech notes on What Makes A Community Tick?, March 20, 1946 (Box 6)
  - SP-48: Speech notes on "Annual County Adult Education Rally and Guest Speaker", April 30, 1947 (Box 6)
  - SP-49: Beware of Genius, March 16, 1932; excerpts of McClusky's speech on how to handle gifted children, appeared in the Washington Post (Box 6)
  - SP-50: The Constructive Use of Change in a Changing society, delivered to the Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development at the 13thAnnual Conference, March 6, 1958 (Box 6)
  - SP-51: Postwar Education and Rehabilitation 1943-44 (Box 6)
  - SP-52: A Speech to Dowagiac Club on Women Activities, 1943-44 (Box 6)
  - SP-53: "Why Scouts Must Grow Today" to the Thirty-Second Annual Meeting of the National Council of the Boy Scouts of America, May 15-16, 1942 (Box 6)
  - SP-54: Youth's Opportunity for a Better Tomorrow, at Banquet Meeting, Youth Section American Country Life Association, Carbondale, Illinois, November 6, 1942 (Box 6)
  - SP-54.1: Adult as learner, University of Michigan, May 18, 1977 (Box 6)
  - SP-54.2: The older adult: Potential in the church religious setting, Sandusky, OH, September 27, 1977 (Box 6)
  - SP-54.3: NUEA presentations, April 22, 1967 (Box 6)
  - SP-55: Adventure and the Emerging Roles of the Adult Education Leader, at NUEA Michigan Union, April 24, 1967 (Box 6)
  - SP-56: Speech notes on "The Unused Powers of the Human Mind", January 20, 1954 (Box 6)
  - SP-57: Youth and the Crisis of Brotherhood, 1943-1944 (Box 6)
  - SP-58: Speech notes on Problems of Maladjustment, March 26, 1935 (Box 6)
  - SP-59: Speech notes on youth, March 15, 1935 (Box 6)
  - SP-60: Some speech notes on books, properties (Library), Summer 1933 (Box 6)
  - SP-61: Don't Have to Put Up With Nothing Fatalistic, April 12, 1956 (Box 6)
  - SP-62: Speech notes on The Brief History of Mental Health Movement, undated (Box 6)
  - SP-63: Speech on Free Enterprise, undated (Box 6)
  - SP-64: Goodwill conference, September 18, 1948 (Box 6)
  - SP-65: Deepest desire (of human beings) is self-preservation, undated (Box 6)
  - SP-66: Human Relations, July 2, 1963 (Box 6)
  - SP-66.1: Institute for training counselors of adults, January 9, 1947 (Box 6)
  - SP-66.2: Challenge of adult education, July 22, 1948 (Box 6)
  - SP-66.3: Agricultural Extension and Adult Education, Ames, Iowa, December 13, 1951 (Box 6)
  - SP-67: "The Adult Learner Tomorrow," Frontenac County Board of Education, January 10, 1979 (Box 6)
  - SP-68: What Mental Hygiene Means for Teaching (notes), undated (Box 6)
  - SP-70: Notes for speech to the Older Rural Youth Committee, April 8, 1940 (Box 6)
  - SP-71: Speech notes for Farm Family Project, April 30, 1940 (Box 6)
  - SP-72: Speech notes on Partnership in Community Life, October 18, 1964 (Box 6)
  - SP-73: The Life-Centered-home and the Child Centered Community, April 2, 1945 (Box 6)
  - SP-74: "For youth - Tomorrow Begins Today," Annual 4-H Club Congress, December 3, 1944 (Box 6)
  - SP-75: The Mental Hygiene of the Teacher, March 9, 1945 (Box 6)
  - SP-76: Impact of War on School and Community Relations, March 9, 1945 (Box 6)
  - SP-77: Impact of Atomic Energy Not Yet Felt, undated (Box 6)
  - SP-78: Speech points to a meeting of the First Baptist Church, November 16, 1947 (Box 6)
  - SP-79: Volunteer and Community (notes), January 12, 1948 (Box 6)
  - SP-80: High School Self-Government Student Councils Meetings, November 7, 1948 (Box 6)
  - SP-81: Looking at Ourselves, undated (Box 6)
  - SP-82: Speech notes, possibly on rural youth (Box 6)
  - SP-83: Speech notes on Education, Health, undated (Box 6)
  - SP-84: Speech notes on Strategy for a Peace Offensive, Kalamazoo, Michigan, June 1, 1949 (Box 6)
  - SP-85: The Camping Movement comes of Age: Its Social Responsibility, March 15, 1947 (Box 6)
  - SP-86: Face to face interaction: Why this Process is Powerful, February 14, 1956 (Box 7)
  - SP-87: Speech notes on margin at Madonna College, March 26, 1981 (Box 7)
  - SP-88: Speech notes on margin at Indianapolis Airport Hilton, September 9, 1981 (Box 7)
  - SP-89: The Next Step, undated (Box 7)
  - SP-90: Why Scouting Must Grow Today, 1942 (Box 7)
  - SP-92: On the American Youth Commission, December 22, 1941 (Box 7)
  - SP-93: An address to a Conference on "The Investment of Life", undated (Box 7)
  - SP-96: The Functions of Education, undated (Box 7)
  - SP-99: Key Issues in Public School Adult Education Today, October 27, 1962 (Box 7)
  - SP-102: Some Problems of Adolescence, WJR Radio Speech, January 25, 1931 (Box 7)
  - SP-103: Importance, needs, and characteristics of young adults, Young Adult Section Meeting, National Adult Education Conference, 1959 (Box 7)
  - SP-104: What do we know about community self-help? Detroit, Michigan, July 14, 1959 (Box 7)
  - SP-105: The idea of a community, East Lansing, Michigan, May 19, 1958 (Box 7)
  - SP-106: The constructive use of change in a changing society, Seattle, Washington, March 6, 1958 (Box 7)
  - SP-107: New directions in school-community relations, Detroit, Michigan, August 29, 1960 (Box 7)
  - SP-108: Conference-seminar on leadership in continuing education, East Lansing, Michigan, June 18, 1958 (Box 7)
  - SP-109: General summary, National Conference on Human Rights, Philadelphia, February 3, 1958 (Box 7)
  - SP-110: Trow-Walcutt-McClelland Recognition Dinner, May 2, 1964 (Box 7)
  - SP-111: Adult education research – a fifty-year perspective, Adult Education Research Conference, Ann Arbor, Michigan, April 14, 1979 (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous writings
  - MS-2: The information self help approach to community development, abstract (Box 7)
  - MS-3: Coordinating community-wide bodies, undated (Box 7)
  - MS-4: An Experimental Study of Language Patterns, by Howard Y. McClusky and Creighton Coleman, undated (Box 7)
  - MS-5: A Quantitative Analysis of the Difficulty of Reading Materials, undated; research report (Box 7)
  - MS-6: The Development of the Child Guidance Clinic, introduction/preface, undated (Box 7)
  - MS-7: Is the Rural School Obsolete?, September 10, 1945; McClusky being interviewed by Xion (Box 7)
  - MS-8: The Future of Adult Education, London-Ontario, May 21, 1943 (Box 7)
  - MS-9: What's Ahead in Education, undated (Box 7)
  - MS-10: Aging and Organization for Community Action, undated (Box 7)
  - MS-11: Notes for a class lecture, January 28, 1981 (Box 7)
  - MS-12: Notes for speech in Dallas, undated (Box 7)
  - MS-13: Notes for speech or lecture, undated (Box 7)
  - MS-14: Notes for speech or lecture, May 18, 1977 (Box 7)
  - MS-15: Community and Adult Education Excerpt, the University of Michigan School of Education Bulletin, April-May 1955 (Box 7)
  - MS-16: Notes for staff meeting, January 19, 1949 (Box 7)
  - MS-17: School-Community Relations, undated; working/first draft (Box 7)
  - MS-19: Notes on Approaching a Period of Decision on Liberal Arts Colleges, Foundations, Industry, Land Grant Colleges, undated (Box 7)
  - MS-20: Notes on Psychology #2 Commitments - obligations (Box 7)
  - MS-23: Lecture notes from lecture on Adult Learning, May 24, 1969 (Box 7)
  - MS-24: Notes on Persons, Agencies and Organizations, Smaller Community, February 28, 1957 (Box 7)
  - MS-25: Conclusion to Flint Adult Education Story (Box 7)
  - MS-26: Notes on Psychology of Adults (Box 7)
  - MS-27: Some propositions in support of the community school – a summary, August 17, 1959 (Box 7)
  - MS-28: The State of Youth in Our Culture, undated (Box 7)
  - MS-29: Notes on Revolutionary Lines, undated (Box 7)
  - MS-30: Adult Dimensions of Lifelong Learning: Reflections on the Future of the Educational Enterprise, Fall 1976 (Box 7)
  - MS-31: Adult Education in Oak Park, Michigan, undated; report; author not indicated but seems to be McClusky's work (Box 7)
  - MS-32: Continuing and Adult Education: A New Challenge to Higher Education, undated; no author indicated, but it seems to be McClusky's work (Box 7)
  - MS-33: Social Responsibility of the Gifted Child, undated; author not indicated but it seems to be McClusky's work (Box 7)
  - MS-34: An Educational Strategy for Cultural Renewal, undated; part of article/presentation; author not indicated, but it seems to be McClusky’s work (Box 7)